with two really good players, two
players that were
high on our board at positions that, you
know, we say are premium positions. So,
to be able to get Avion here. What a
cool experience for him, his family to
be able to play alongside of his
brother. It was fun being able to call
both of them and and hear their
excitement. And then uh
you know, for us to get Zachariah, you
know, in in three. Um a player that
we're really excited about. Our coaching
staff was excited about. I mean, our
coaching staff was excited about all the
picks. So, it was just really cool. It
was a really cool experience. Um
and we're excited. So, we'll open up for
questions.
Kevin, AJ was on with us after the pick
with Avion. He said that you you tipped
him off. Mhm. I had permission from this
guy.
>> [laughter]
>> It was early and he had to kind of like
hold his breath and not give anything
away. What was that conversation like
with him? Yeah, it was Ian's idea to,
you know, show respect to AJ and and let
him know kind of what was in the works.
Obviously, there was no guarantee that
Avion was going to still be there at at
that time, but just felt like we wanted
to give him a a heads-up. So, you said
your brother is there. He's about to
pick. That's right.
With Zach, just
his role, kind of how do you see him
here and what kind of attracted
um
y'all to him at that spot? We've
Ian and crew have done a ton of work on
Zachariah. Had him in here for a visit.
We've spent a lot of time with him. The
coaches have and uh he really has a a
great schematic fit, also a great
personal fit for for what we believe in
and and how hard he works, but just a a
player that you can really line up all
over the field. You go back and watch
his tape over the course of his
different stops and the way he was
utilized. I think there's a ton of
versatility there. And also, he provides
value in in the return game, which is no
small thing. What I would hear last year
was
quick, right? I mean, is there more
there in him do you feel like? Yeah, I
think with any player at any position,
you look at how they're utilized and
there may be different ways that you
envision to use them. Bottom line, he
was a very very productive player
for the Bulldogs and and there's things
that that we love that he did
with them that that we'll continue to
lean into.
Does does having
AJ in the building change at all the way
you're looking at Avion's kind of
on-ramp into connect acclimated with the
team, with the the playbook, anything
like that?
Uh
you know, I think it's obviously it's a
very unique. This is very cool.
But, we're also excited about just you
know, Avion's role and growing into
being the best version of himself. And
you know, we talked about this earlier
in this process how how we look at this
as a
chance to bring in really good players
to this football team that are going to
help us, but also they're they're going
to develop and and he's going to be
somebody that we get our arms around and
we bring him along and we I know this
knowing what I know about him and he'll
he'll work and work and work. And that's
what we're excited about.
Ian, with Avion, was he
targeted? Were you thinking of him
before the round began? This [snorts] is
guy we want or did it kind of fall
all the way down to you?
Yeah, um
it's funny, we we did some of our
scenarios and strategies this morning
and
um Matt asked a great question. And it
was like, who's who are the guys that
you wouldn't trade off of, right? And
um Avion was our number one guy. And we
didn't think that he would be there.
Uh so, we were excited when he was
there.
Um and we were able to pull the trigger.
Your number one guy overall, Rick?
>> No, no, just coming into the day. Yeah,
coming into the day.
>> back or at any position?
>> At any position coming into the day. I I
I'm sorry, not at any position coming
into the day. Just one of the guys that
I would we would not trade off of.
Sorry. Yeah, no sweat. Thanks. In your
evaluation of him,
did you have to at any point separate
how how cool it would be with just a
strict evaluation of the player, you
know, as you were stacking cornerbacks?
Say that one more time, Josh. Sorry. In
terms of your evaluation of the player,
of Avion as a player, you know, did you
have to guard yourself against thinking,
yeah, that would also be cool and just
sort of grade him dispassionately? In
terms of outside of being AJ's brother.
Oh, yeah. We just we think about the
player. Yeah, um it would have
you know, AJ's obviously a really good
player, but you know, um Avion's his own
man. And to be able to just grade him
for who he was and who he is,
um
he's we're excited to get him. He's
tough, competitive, scrappy.
Um plays the ball, plays the game the
way that we want our guys to play. So,
we're just excited to get a player of
this caliber at the at the
uh point of the draft where we got him.
It is your first day making picks. Just
how would you assess how, you know, the
day went in terms of that aspect of it?
I feel like it went smooth. You know, it
was a really good communication
throughout the day. It was
um everybody was seemed to be enjoying
themselves, right?
>> [snorts]
>> So, it was it was a good day. It was
fun.
I know you guys weren't the ones last
year that brought in Jaylen Walker, but
it is the second year in a row that a
dog is here brought to Atlanta. I'm sure
the fans appreciate that trend. Just
what do you think about that aspect of
things of, you know, creating maybe a
pipeline for Georgia?
Yeah, I feel like we we've we've shared
this a lot and we'll I'm sure we will
continue to.
You know, what they've done and what
they continue to do at Georgia, um
they're always going to have uh you
know, really good football players,
right? And it's cool that it's right in
our backyard. So, we're going to
continue to build those relationships
and
foster [clears throat] those
relationships there
and look forward to scouting future
Bulldogs in the future. Yeah.
I was going to Kirby's excited.
>> [laughter]
>> That he's that he's coming. So, uh we
you know, like Ian said, that's a hell
of a program they have down there and uh
we're excited to add
a Bulldog today. I just wanted to ask
that Ian, at any point were you close to
a trade and that's still something that
could be a possibility tomorrow or even
tonight? Yeah, um we'll see what happens
what happens tomorrow. We I felt like
the guys upstairs, you know, with Jeff
Scott, with Tombo, with Shawn and Rossy,
you know, we've had and and Matt, we've
had some really good conversations
today. Um talked to teams, but nothing
came to fruition at the end.
Zachariah had an incident earlier this
week. Did that affect affect your
evaluation at all?
It didn't affect the evaluation of the
player. We're obviously well aware of
the incident. Um but didn't affect our
evaluation.
>> impact on the way you felt about the
player? Correct.
Ian, obviously last year Zachariah, a
lot of his
usage came short area, behind line of
scrimmage. Did you see enough in in past
film to feel comfortable that his game
can expand here in Atlanta? Yeah, we
we've we've talked about it. We we've
gone back and watched some of his USC
tape and
think you get to see him run more
say more routes on the route tree at USC
and you have a even greater appreciation
for the skill set and what he's able to
do and and and and coach just touched on
a lot of that. So, we feel excited about
the player, what we're going to be able
to do with him and excited to get him in
the building here tomorrow.
Coach, I know you spoke about the unique
of the just the uniqueness overall about
the Terrell brothers and having Have you
had a situation before in your coaching
career
>> [laughter]
>> You guys tell me. I don't know. Have I?
Uh yeah, I
again,
it's a unique story in this league and
you know, happy for them and their
family. We're excited about
what Avion can bring to this football
team. You know, in our work with him in
this pre-draft process, just
understanding who he is
on his own and and the person that he
is. It's a it's a really good fit for
our locker room. It's really good fit
for our football team.
Avion's a guy that's pretty versatile.
Do you guys have a vision for,
you know, where he might play outside of
nickel? Uh we do and that's obviously
something that coach Ulbrich and and
coach Hood we're we're talking through
all those things. Uh
you know,
you can never have enough good corners.
I worked for Mike Zimmer and I've heard
that from him many many times. So, we're
we're excited to add
a good player to a room full of good
players. You mentioned the positional
clips on Monday
and and did do you based off of your
early assessment of how the draft board
would fall,
did it kind of go the way that you
anticipated?
>> No.
No.
It's funny, we were like uh coming into
today,
we didn't anticipate there to be as many
corners, you know, on the board. And it
look
we were rewarded. So, um
we'll see what happens tomorrow.
Chris, there was a development James and
Kirksey commenting on what's this
treatment situation. Yeah, we're just
talking about the players that we we
drafted tonight.
their day and we're excited for that.
We'll talk about that in another time.
Anything that tempted you yesterday in
the first round? Anything that got close
in conversations? Any
Uh no.
No.
>> [laughter]
>> No.
It was it was good to just be able to
sit there and watch.
It's good TV. Yeah.
With Zachariah, um I think he's known
when he was at Georgia, obviously known
for the physical tools are obvious, but
I think
he was someone that Kirby Smart
appreciated because he just was so
dialed in and
he is sponge. Kind of what did that
mean to you and kind of how how can that
help him?
Yeah, I I think you saw you get that
when you sit across from Zachariah, you
talk to him. You understand what he's
about, how much how passionate he is
about this game. He loves this game and
he loves to be out there and and working
in practice. So, uh
you know,
coaches appreciate those of guys that
that bring it every single day, that
bring the juice every single day. Um, so
I again, that's why I think the fit here
uh
we can talk through the schematic fit,
but the the personal fit, the culture
fit, the the the fit in our locker room,
the fit in what we believe in is really
strong.
And you touched on a little bit of that
again, but just like the actual moment
of
saying this is our pick with the second
round pick. Was that kind of a moment
for you of
you know, I'm of realizing kind of where
you are and then to be in this position?
Um, it was uh
it was awesome, man. It was uh it was
kind of cool just to kind of get it.
Didn't even think that Avion was going
to be there, right? And uh to get that
prepped up and having the help of
everybody in the room,
we were well prepared. Um, but in terms
of thinking about it for me, maybe I'll
think about it later tonight, but in the
moment, I I just didn't want to mess up.
Uh feel like it turned out well. What
I'm this last question, what what are
the mechanics of it? Like do you do you
think tell someone that here's our pick
or are you calling to the league? Yeah,
so yeah.
Try to be prepared. Uh give the give
Steph three names, uh the order that we
would pick them in.
Uh she'll write those names down. Uh and
then once we know that we're on the
clock, she'll erase the last two names
and then we'll give the player like in
this case the last instance it was
Zachariah. And then Mike Gross will call
the
uh the player and then I'll talk to the
player and then hand it off to Kevin.
They'll submit the name, so we have a a
pretty good process.
Anything else? This is sort of also
frivolous, but like the the fact that I
mean, I know you're not picking guys
with where they're from in mind, but you
get a Georgia guy, you get a kid from
Westlake whose brother a player.
Did and you're obviously had have are
from here also. Was there a moment like
kind of recognize like, oh, this kind of
worked out in a neat way for us that for
the fans will be happy about it or
anything like that?
Yeah, we're we're happy we're happy to
get two really good players, you know,
at positions that can come in here and
help us um in the locker room, on the
field, and in the community.
All right. Thank you. Well, thank you
guys. Thanks, guys. Thanks. Appreciate
it.
>> [music]